Register of The Militant Photographic Collection
Hoover Institution Archives
The Militant Photographic Collection
circa 1900-2000
2004C51
48 manuscript boxes (19.2 linear feet)
Hoover Institution on War, Revolution, and Peace Stanford, California 94305-6010
Photographs, drawings, and printed reproductions of illustrations, depicting activities of antiwar, civil rights, labor, racial justice, women's rights and other protest movements in the United States and other countries, mainly from the 1960s through the 1990s. Includes many photographs from Cuba and Nicaragua. Also includes photographs depicting activities of the Socialist Workers Party in the United States and of related organizations in the United States and abroad. Collected by the New York newspaper The Militant for use in illustrating its issues.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open for research. Access to audiovisual materials requires at least two weeks advance notice. Audiovisual materials include sound recordings, video recordings, and motion picture film. Hoover staff will determine whether use copies of the materials requested can be made available. Some materials may not be accessible even with advance notice. Please contact the Hoover Institution Archives Audiovisual Specialist for further information.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 2004.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Historical Note
The Militant began publication in New York City in 1928 as the weekly newspaper of the Communist League of America, whose leaders had just been expelled from the Communist Party, U.S.A. The Communist League of America was a part of the International Left Opposition of the communist movement led by Leon Trotsky. The Militant has continued publication in close association with the Socialist Workers Party, successor to the Communist League of America. The Anchor Foundation donated the collection to the Hoover Institution Archives in 2004.
Scope and Content of Collection
The Militant Photographic Collection consists of pictorial material created or collected by the staff of The Militant for possible publication as in the newspaper. The material varies considerably in composition, including original photographic prints and contact sheets made by The Militant staff members during the course of reporting trips, stock photographic prints received from other sources, and some printed illustrations from published media sources. There are also a few original cartoons. While there is some older material, most of it dates from the period of the 1960s to the 1990s. Aside from a small series of cartoons, the collection is arranged in two large series, corresponding to domestic (United States) and international (non-U.S.) subjects respectively.
Domestic subjects that are especially well represented include the antiwar movement from the Vietnam War on, labor strikes and union organization efforts, the civil rights movement and efforts to secure racial justice and equality, and the women's rights movement, including abortion rights advocacy. Photographs of mass demonstrations and other protests are especially notable. Other domestic photographs portray leaders and activities of the Socialist Workers Party and its youth group and of the affiliated Pathfinder Press and The Militant.
The international series includes photographs from almost every country in the world. They depict world leaders, political and military events, mass demonstrations, and social and economic conditions. Particularly voluminous and notable are photographs resulting from The Militant reporting trips to Cuba, Nicaragua, El Salvador, Grenada, post-1990 South Africa and post-1975 Vietnam.
Users of The Militant Photographic Collection should be aware of the closely related Pathfinder Press Photographic Collection also in the Hoover Institution Archives. The Militant Photographic Collection includes only a small number of negatives, but, in many cases, negatives corresponding to photographic prints in it may be found in the Pathfinder Press Photographic Collection. The Pathfinder Press Photographic Collection includes a large series of negatives arranged in numerical order. Negatives corresponding to prints in both collections are interfiled in this series and may be located by consulting negative numbers written on the backs of prints.
Arrangement
Arranged into three series: Cartoons, Domestic (United States) Scenes, and International (Non-United States) Scenes. Arranged alphabetically within series.
Indexing Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the library's online public access catalog.
Subjects
Protest movements--Pictorial works.; Peace movements--Pictorial works.; Civil rights--Pictorial works.; Labor movement--Pictorial works.; Race relations--Pictorial works.; Women's rights--Pictorial works.; Protest movements--United States.; Peace movements--United States.; Civil rights--United States.; Labor movement--United States.; United States--Race relations.; Women's rights--United States.; Cuba--Pictorial works.; Nicaragua--Pictorial works.; Socialism--Pictorial works.; Communism--Pictorial works.; Socialist Workers Party--Pictorial works.; Fourth International--Pictorial works.; Militant (New York, N.Y.)
Container List
- Cartoons. (Box 1)
  Original drawings and printed reproductions
  - Original drawings
    - Jacobs and David (Folder 1: 1)
    - Licho, Ivan (Folder 1: 2)
  - Printed reproductions
    - Blacks/Afro-Americans (Folder 1: 3)
    - Capitalist parties and politicians (Folder 1: 4)
    - Economy, prices and unemployment (Folder 1: 5)
    - International events (Folder 1: 6)
    - Labor (Folder 1: 7)
    - Police surveillance and civil liberties (Folder 1: 8)
    - Prisoners (Folder 1: 9)
    - Socialist Workers Party and Young Socialist Alliance (Folder 1: 10)
    - Southern Africa (Folder 1: 11)
    - U.S. government (Folder 1: 12)
    - War (Folder 1: 13)
    - Women (Folder 1: 14)
- Domestic (United States) Scenes.
  Photographic prints, contact sheets, and printed reproductions. Arranged alphabetically by subject.
  - Anti-nuclear energy movement
    - Three-Mile Island protests, 1979 (Folder 1: 15)
    - General (Folder 1: 16-17)
  - Antiwar movement demonstrations and protests
    - Bring the Troops Home movement, 1945 (Folder 1: 18)
    - Pre-1965 (Folder 1: 19)
    - 1965-1968 (Folder 1: 20)
    - 1969 (Folder 1: 21)
    - 1970 (Folder 1: 22)
    - Kent State University, 1970 May 4 (Folder 1: 23)
    - 1971 April 24 (Folder 1: 24)
    - 1971 November 6 (Folder 1: 25)
    - 1972 April 22-29 (Folder 1: 26)
    - 1972 May 5 (Folder 1: 27)
    - 1972 Fall (Folder 1: 28)
    - 1973 January 20 (Box-folder 2: 1)
    - 1973 post-ceasefire (Folder 2: 2)
    - Vietnam War era (various dates)
      - General (Folder 2: 3-4)
      - General—Contact sheets (Folder 2: 5)
      - Black participants (Folder 2: 6)
      - Conferences (Folder 2: 7)
      - GIs—Fort Jackson 8 (Folder 2: 8)
      - GIs and veterans (Folder 2: 9)
      - High school participants (Folder 2: 10)
      - Hispanic participants (Folder 2: 11)
      - Labor participants (Folder 2: 12)
      - Police confrontations and ultralefts (Folder 2: 13)
      - Socialist Workers Party/Young Socialist Alliance banners (Folder 2: 14-15)
      - Student Mobilization Committee (Folder 2: 16)
      - Women and children participants (Folder 2: 17)
    - Anti-draft protests, 1980 (Folder 2: 18)
    - 1982 June 12 (Folder 2: 19)
    - Anti-nuclear weapon protests (Folder 2: 20)
    - Central America protests, 1978-1985 (Box-folder 3: 1)
    - 1985 April 20 (Folder 3: 2)
    - Central America protests, 1986-1988 (Folder 3: 3)
    - Ben Linder protests, 1987 (Folder 3: 4)
    - Brian Willson protests, 1987 (Folder 3: 5)
    - 1987 April 25
      - General (Folder 3: 6)
      - Contact sheets (Folder 3: 7)
    - Veterans peace convoy, 1988 (Folder 3: 8)
    - Central America protests (various dates)
      - General (Folder 3: 9)
      - Contact sheets (Folder 3: 10)
    - Anti-Strategic Defense Initiative-III protest, 1988 June 11 (Folder 3: 11)
    - Gulf War protests, 1991
      - General (Folder 3: 12-13)
      - Contact sheets (Folder 3: 14)
    - Post-Gulf War protests, 1998 (Folder 3: 15)
  - Armed forces
    - Air Force (Folder 3: 16)
    - Army (Folder 3: 17)
    - Marine Corps (Folder 3: 18)
    - Navy (Folder 3: 19)
  - Asian Americans (Folder 3: 20)
  - Budget cut protests
    - Pre-1990s (Folder 3: 21)
    - 1990s (Folder 3: 22)
  - Capitalist institutions (stock market, etc.) (Folder 3: 23)
  - Child care protests, 1970s (Folder 3: 24)
  - Cities, poverty, and housing (Folder 3: 25)
  - Civil rights, anti-racism, and black/Afro-American struggles
    - Slavery (Folder 3: 26)
    - Civil War (Folder 3: 27)
    - Radical Reconstruction (Folder 3: 28)
    - South, Jim Crow era (Folder 3: 29)
    - 1930s to 1950s (Folder 3: 30)
    - South, 1960s (Box-folder 4: 1)
    - North, 1960s (Folder 4: 2-3)
    - Ghetto rebellions, 1960s (Folder 4: 4-5)
    - Lowndes County, Georgia, voter registration, 1966 (Folder 4: 6)
    - Memphis demonstrations, 1968 (Folder 4: 7)
    - Black Panther Party, 1968-1970 (Folder 4: 8)
    - Community control protests, 1960s and 1970s (Folder 4: 9)
    - Cairo, Illinois, united front, 1970 (Folder 4: 10)
    - STRESS protest, Detroit, 1973 (Folder 4: 11)
    - National Black Political Conventions
      - Gary, Indiana, 1972 (Folder 4: 12)
      - Little Rock, Arkansas, 1974 (Folder 4: 13)
    - National Black Independent Political Party, 1970s and 1980s (Folder 4: 14)
    - Busing, 1970s
      - General (Folder 4: 15)
      - Anti-busing demonstrations (Folder 4: 16)
      - National Student Coalition against Racism (Folder 4: 17)
      - Boston
        - General (Folder 4: 18)
        - 1974 November 30 (Folder 4: 19)
        - 1974 December 24 (Folder 4: 20)
        - 1975 May 17 (Folder 4: 21)
        - Carson Beach, 1977 July 22 (Folder 4: 22)
      - Chicago (Folder 4: 23)
      - Los Angeles (Folder 4: 24)
      - Louisville (Folder 4: 25)
    - Operation PUSH, 1970s and 1980s (Folder 4: 26)
    - Affirmative action protests, 1970s to 1990s (Folder 4: 27)
    - National Association for the Advancement of Colored People and Southern Christian Leadership Conference, 1970s to 1990s (Folder 4: 28)
    - Miami protests, 1980 (Folder 4: 29)
    - Atlanta child murder protests, 1981 (Folder 4: 30)
    - Martin Luther King Day marches
      - 1981 (Folder 4: 31)
      - 1982 (Folder 4: 32)
      - 1986 and 1988 (Folder 4: 33)
    - MOVE, 1985 (Folder 4: 34)
    - Sagon Penn protests, 1985 (Folder 4: 35)
    - Voting rights protests, 1985 (Folder 4: 36)
    - Howard Beach protests, New York City, 1986-1987 (Folder 4: 37)
    - Clarence Brandley protests, 1987 (Folder 4: 38)
    - Jimmy Lee Bruce protests, 1987 (Folder 4: 39)
    - Forsyth County, Georgia, protests, 1987 (Folder 4: 40)
    - Greensboro, North Carolina, anti-Ku Kluk Klan protests, 1987 (Folder 4: 41)
    - Yusuf Hawkins protests, 1989 (Folder 4: 42)
    - 1980s and 1990s (Box 5)
      - General (Folder 5: 1-2)
      - Contact sheets (Folder 5: 3-4)
    - March on Washington anniversaries, 1983 and 1993 (Folder 5: 5)
  - Communist Party (Folder 5: 6)
  - Death penalty protests (Folder 5: 7-8)
  - Defense cases
    - Abu-Jamal, Mumia (Folder 5: 9)
    - Alabama coalfield workers (Folder 5: 10)
    - Attica prisoners (Folder 5: 11)
    - Banks, Dennis (Folder 5: 12)
    - Bird, Joan (Folder 5: 13)
    - Bloomington 3 (Folder 5: 14)
    - Brooklyn Navy Yard workers (Folder 5: 15)
    - Camden 28 (Folder 5: 16)
    - Carter, Hurricane (Folder 5: 17)
    - Carthan, Eddie, and Tchula 7 (Folder 5: 18)
    - Charlotte 3 (Folder 5: 19)
    - Chicago 7 (Folder 5: 20)
    - Curtis, Mark
      - General (Folder 5: 21)
      - Contact sheets
        - General (Folder 5: 22)
        - 1988 (Folder 5: 23)
        - 1989 (Folder 5: 24)
        - 1990 (Folder 5: 25)
      - Curtis after police beating (Box-folder 6: 1)
      - Curtis campaigning before incarceration (Folder 6: 2)
      - Trial, 1988 September (Folder 6: 3)
      - Support work (Folder 6: 4)
      - Prominent supporters (Folder 6: 5)
      - Curtis family (Folder 6: 6)
      - Kaku, Kate (Folder 6: 7)
      - Censorship aspects (Folder 6: 8)
      - Countercampaign (Folder 6: 9)
      - Curtis alone (Folder 6: 10)
      - Curtis with others (Folder 6: 11)
      - Release from prison (Folder 6: 12)
      - After release (Folder 6: 13)
    - Davis, Angela (Folder 6: 14)
    - Domingo and Viernes (Folder 6: 15)
    - Dzhemilev, Mustafa (Folder 6: 16)
    - Freedom Socialist Party, Seattle (Folder 6: 17)
    - Gainesville 8 (Folder 6: 18)
    - Garrison, Gary (Folder 6: 19)
    - Goodman, Sally (Folder 6: 20)
    - Grigorenko, Pyotr (Folder 6: 21)
    - Hariri-Vijeh, Mojgan (Folder 6: 22)
    - Hartford 15 (Folder 6: 23)
    - Hobby (Folder 6: 24)
    - Houston 12 (Folder 6: 25)
    - Johnson, J. B. (Folder 6: 26)
    - Little, Joanne (Folder 6: 27)
    - Lockheed 9 (Folder 6: 28)
    - Lopez, Jesse (Folder 6: 29)
    - Los Angeles 8 (Folder 6: 30)
    - Loudhawk, Kenneth, and Russell Redner (Folder 6: 31)
    - Marroquin, Hector (Folder 6: 32)
    - Martinez, Francisco "Kiko" (Folder 6: 33)
    - Mendoza, Ray (Box-folder 7: 1)
    - Menominee Warriors Society (Folder 7: 2)
    - Morales, William (Folder 7: 3)
    - Peltier, Leonard (Folder 7: 4)
    - Pit River 38 (Folder 7: 5)
    - Plyushch, Leonid (Folder 7: 6)
    - Pontiac Brothers (Folder 7: 7)
    - Puerto Rican 5 (Folder 7: 8)
    - Rosenberg, Julius and Ethel (Folder 7: 9)
    - Sacco, Nicolo, and Bartolomeo Vanzetti (Folder 7: 10)
    - Santiago, Wilfredo (Folder 7: 11)
    - Los Siete de la Raza (Folder 7: 12)
    - Simon, Private Lewis (Folder 7: 13)
    - Sioux Falls Indian defendants (Folder 7: 14)
    - Skyhorse, Paul, and Richard Mohawk (Folder 7: 15)
    - Soledad Brothers (Folder 7: 16)
    - Los Tres (Folder 7: 17)
    - Tyler, Gary (Folder 7: 18)
    - Wilmington 10 (Folder 7: 19)
    - Worthy, William (Folder 7: 20)
    - Miscellaneous (current in 1990s) (Folder 7: 21)
  - Democratic rights protests (Folder 7: 22)
  - Deportation protests
    - 1970s and 1980s (Folder 7: 23)
    - Swift 17, Des Moines (Folder 7: 24)
  - Drug testing protests (Folder 7: 25)
  - Earthquakes (Folder 7: 26)
  - Environmental protests
    - General (includes anti-nuclear energy protests) (Folder 7: 27)
    - Exxon oil spill, Valdez, Alaska (Folder 7: 28)
    - Love Canal, PCB, plutonium (Folder 7: 29)
  - Farming and farm protests
    - Farming (Folder 7: 30)
    - Protests
      - Pre-1984 (Folder 7: 31)
      - 1984 (Folder 7: 32)
      - 1985 (Folder 7: 33)
      - 1990s (Folder 7: 34)
    - Federation of Southern Co-ops (Folder 7: 35)
    - Contact sheets (Folder 7: 36)
  - Gay rights protests (Folder 7: 37)
  - Hawaii—Protests (Folder 7: 38)
  - Health care protests
    - General (Folder 7: 39)
    - AIDS (Folder 7: 40)
    - Sydenham Hospital, New York City (Folder 7: 41)
  - Hispanic/chicano rights
    - General (Folder 7: 42)
    - Chicano Moratorium, Los Angeles (Folder 7: 43)
    - Crusade for Justice, Denver (Folder 7: 44)
    - Culture (Folder 7: 45)
    - Immigration protests (Folder 7: 46)
    - La Raza Unida Party
      - General (Folder 7: 47)
      - Crystal City, Texas (Folder 7: 48)
    - Union support (Folder 7: 49)
  - Historical background (19th and early 20th centuries) (Box 8)
    - General (Folder 8: 1)
    - Civil War (Folder 8: 2)
  - House Un-American Activities Committee—Protests against (Folder 8: 3)
  - Immigration rights protests (Folder 8: 4)
  - Indian/Native American rights
    - Historical background (Folder 8: 5)
    - Wounded Knee trial, 1973
      - General (Folder 8: 6)
      - Defendants (Folder 8: 7)
    - 1970s (Folder 8: 8)
    - 1980s and 1990s (Folder 8: 9)
    - American Indian Movement (Folder 8: 10)
    - Contact sheets (Folder 8: 11)
  - Industrial Workers of the World (Folder 8: 12)
  - Labor
    - Historical background (Folder 8: 13)
    - AFL-CIO
      - Conventions (Folder 8: 14)
      - Demonstrations (Folder 8: 15)
      - Solidarity Day, 1981 (Folder 8: 16)
    - Aerospace/airlines workers
      - Machinists (Folder 8: 17)
      - Non-machinists (Folder 8: 18)
      - PATCO strike, 1981 (Folder 8: 19)
      - Eastern Airlines strike, 1989-1990
        - Machinists (Folder 8: 20)
        - Pilots and flight attendants (Folder 8: 21)
        - Other airport workers (Folder 8: 22)
        - Picket lines (Folder 8: 23)
        - Walkthroughs and other actions (Folder 8: 24)
        - Outreach to other struggles (Folder 8: 25)
        - Support from other unions and students (Folder 8: 26)
      - Boeing strike, 1995 (Folder 8: 27)
    - Auto workers
      - 1930s and 1940s (Folder 8: 28-29)
      - 1950s to 1970s (Box-folder 9: 1)
      - Industrial production, 1980s (Folder 9: 2)
      - Caterpillar workers, 1990s (Folder 9: 3)
    - Communication workers (Folder 9: 4)
    - Construction workers
      - General (Folder 9: 5)
      - Drywallers strike, 1992 (Folder 9: 6)
    - Electrical workers
      - 1940s (Folder 9: 7-8)
      - 1970s to 1990s (Folder 9: 9)
    - Farm workers
      - United Farm Workers
        - General (Folder 9: 10)
        - Teamsters conflict, 1973 (Folder 9: 11)
        - Organizer funeral, Delano, 1973 (Folder 9: 12)
        - Gallo strike and boycott, 1973 (Folder 9: 13)
        - Delano and Modesto marches (Folder 9: 14)
        - 1980s (Folder 9: 15)
        - 1990s (Folder 9: 16)
      - United Farm Workers of Washington State (Folder 9: 17)
      - FLOC (Folder 9: 18)
      - PCUN, Oregon (Folder 9: 19)
      - Other (Folder 9: 20)
    - Garment/textile workers
      - Historical background (Folder 9: 21-22)
      - Working conditions (Folder 9: 23)
      - Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers Union (Folder 9: 24)
      - International Ladies' Garment Workers Union (Folder 9: 25)
      - UNITE (Folder 9: 26)
    - Health care workers (Folder 9: 27)
    - Hotel/restaurant workers (Folder 9: 28)
    - Longshoremen
      - 1934 strike (Folder 9: 29)
      - 1959 strike (Folder 9: 30)
      - 1990s (Folder 9: 31)
    - Meatpackers
      - 1930s and 1940s (Folder 9: 32)
      - 1980s (Folder 9: 33)
      - Hormel strike, 1986 (Folder 9: 34)
      - 1990s (Folder 9: 35)
      - Working conditions (Folder 9: 36)
      - Related grocery workers (Folder 9: 37)
    - Miners
      - Historical background (Folder 9: 38-39)
      - Brookside, Harlan County and Stearns strikes, 1970s (Folder 9: 40)
      - 1977-1978 strike (Folder 9: 41-42)
      - Massey strike, 1984-1986 (Folder 9: 43)
      - Western strikes, 1987 (Folder 9: 44)
      - Pittston strike, 1989-1990 (Box-folder 10: 1-2)
      - 1989-1991 (Folder 10: 3)
      - Western struggles, 1990s (Folder 10: 4)
      - BCOA strike, 1993 (Folder 10: 5)
      - Peabody strike, 1993 (Folder 10: 6)
      - Other, 1993 (Folder 10: 7-8)
      - Jeddo strike, 1998 (Folder 10: 9)
      - Black lung protests (Folder 10: 10)
      - Mine disasters (Folder 10: 11)
      - Women miners (Folder 10: 12)
      - Working conditions (Folder 10: 13)
    - Newspaper workers
      - General (Folder 10: 14)
      - New York Daily News strike, 1990-1991 (Folder 10: 15)
    - Oil workers
      - 1940s (Folder 10: 16)
      - Strikes, 1970s and 1980s (Folder 10: 17)
      - Strikes, 1990s (Folder 10: 18)
    - Paper workers—Jay, Maine, strike, 1987-1988 (Folder 10: 19)
    - Postal workers (Folder 10: 20)
    - Public employees (teachers, etc.) (Folder 10: 21)
    - Railway workers
      - Historical background (Folder 10: 22)
      - 1980s (Folder 10: 23)
      - 1990s (Folder 10: 24)
      - Industrial conditions (Folder 10: 25)
    - Retail workers—Montgomery Ward strike, 1945 (Folder 10: 26)
    - Shipyard workers
      - 1940s (Folder 10: 27)
      - 1980s (Folder 10: 28)
    - Steelworkers
      - 1930s and 1940s (Folder 10: 29-30)
      - 1950s to 1980s (Folder 10: 31)
      - Newport News strike, 1979 (Folder 10: 32-33)
      - Ravenswood lockout, 1990-1992 (Folder 10: 34)
      - Trinity strike, 1992-1993 (Folder 10: 35)
      - Strikes, 1990s (Folder 10: 36)
    - Teamsters
      - Watsonville strike, 1986 (Folder 10: 37)
      - 1994 (Folder 10: 38)
      - UPS strike, 1997 (Folder 10: 39)
    - Telephone workers, 1940s (Folder 10: 40)
    - Transit workers
      - General (Folder 10: 41)
      - Greyhound strike, 1990 (Folder 10: 42)
    - Miscellaneous workers
      - Historical background (Folder 10: 43-45)
      - 1990s (Box-folder 11: 1)
    - Contact sheets (Folder 11: 2-5)
  - Pathfinder Press/The Militant
    - Newspaper sales
      - General (Folder 11: 6)
      - Plant gates
        - 1970s (Folder 11: 7)
        - 1980s (Folder 11: 8)
        - 1990s (Folder 11: 9)
      - Union events (Folder 11: 10)
    - Bookstores (Box 12)
      - General (Folder 12: 1-2)
      - Vandalism (Folder 12: 3)
    - Book sales displays (Folder 12: 4)
    - Book fairs
      - U.S. (Folder 12: 5)
      - International (Folder 12: 6-8)
      - Tehran, Iran
        - 1994 (Folder 12: 9)
        - 1995 (Folder 12: 10)
    - Book promotions
      - General (Folder 12: 11)
      - Che Guevara and the Cuban Revolution, 1987-1988 (Folder 12: 12)
      - Thomas Sankara Speaks, 1988-1989 (Folder 12: 13)
      - Carlos Tablada tour (re Che Guevara: Economics and Politics in the Transition to Socialism) (Box 13)
        - U.S. and Canada, 1990 (Folder 13: 1)
        - Europe, 1990 (Folder 13: 2)
        - U.S., 1991 (Folder 13: 3)
        - Canada and Europe, 1993 (Folder 13: 4)
      - Nelson Mandela Speaks, 1993-1994 (Folder 13: 5)
    - Karl Marx/Friedrich Engels book rescue, Moscow, Russia, 1992 (Folder 13: 6)
    - Peter Clifford press conference, Belfast, Northern Ireland, 1988 (Folder 13: 7)
    - Pathfinder Building (New York City)
      - Reconstruction
        - 1970s (Folder 13: 8)
        - 1991-1992 (Folder 13: 9)
        - 1993 (Folder 13: 10)
        - Contact sheets (Folder 13: 11)
      - Library reorganization project, 1990s (Folder 13: 12)
      - Pick and pack project, 1996-1997 (Folder 13: 13)
      - Editorial offices, 1990s (Folder 13: 14)
      - Printshop
        - 1970s (Folder 13: 15)
        - 1980s (Folder 13: 16)
        - 1990s (Folder 13: 17)
        - Militant runs, 1998 (Folder 13: 18)
    - Pathfinder Mural
      - General (Folder 13: 19)
      - Progress of painting (Folder 13: 20)
      - Details of mural (Box-folder 14: 1)
      - Artists (Folder 14: 2)
      - Artists with details (Folder 14: 3)
      - Defacement and restoration (Folder 14: 4)
      - Tours and meetings (Folder 14: 5)
      - Slides (Folder 14: 6)
      - Negatives (Folder 14: 7)
  - Police brutality and police brutality protests
    - 1960s and 1970s (Folder 14: 8)
    - 1980s and 1990s
      - Des Moines (Folder 14: 9)
      - Los Angeles (Folder 14: 10)
      - Miami (Folder 14: 11)
      - Minneapolis and St. Paul (Folder 14: 12)
      - New Jersey (Folder 14: 13)
      - New York (Folder 14: 14)
      - Other cities (Folder 14: 15)
      - Contact sheets (Folder 14: 16-17)
  - Prisons (Folder 14: 18)
  - Protectionism (Folder 14: 19)
  - Puerto Ricans (Folder 14: 20)
  - Right-wing groups and protests against
    - General (Folder 14: 21)
    - Anti-communist demonstrations re Poland, 1981 (Folder 14: 22)
    - Buchanan (Pat) group, 1996 (Folder 14: 23)
    - Cuban anti-communists (Folder 14: 24-25)
    - Ku Klux Klan (Box 15)